They're down on their luck and up to their necks in
señoritas, margaritas, banditos and bullets!
¡Three Amigos! is a comedy, western, drama film directed by John Landis.
A trio of unemployed silent film actors are mistaken for real heroes by a small
Mexican village in search of someone to stop a malevolent bandit.
Dusty Bottoms, played by Chevy Chase.
Lucky Day, played by Steve Martin.
Ned Nederlander, played by Martin Short.
El Guapo, played by Alfonso Arau.
Jefe, played by Tony Plana.
Carmen, played by Patrice Martinez.
¡Three Amigos!
is a 1986 American Western comedy film directed by John Landis and written by Steve
Martin, Lorne Michaels, and Randy Newman, who also composed the film's songs.
The film stars Martin, Chevy Chase, and Martin Short as three out-of-work silent film actors who are mistaken for real heroes
by the desperate inhabitants of a small Mexican village under threat from a notorious bandit and his gang.
Produced by Michaels and George Folsey Jr.
for HBO Pictures and L.A.
Films, the film was distributed by Orion Pictures
and released on December 12, 1986.
Despite receiving mixed reviews from critics, it grossed $39.2 million at the box office against a $25 million budget and
has since gained a cult following for its absurdist humor, musical sequences, and ensemble performances.
The film explores themes of hero, mexico, village, usa–mexico border, confusion.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.